Register of the Irwin T. and Shirley Holtzman collection, 1899-2010
Hoover Institution Archives
Irwin T. and Shirley Holtzman collection
1899-2010
98074
Holtzman, Irwin T
Holtzman, Shirley
156 manuscript boxes, 8 oversize boxes, 1 cardfile box, 32 cubic foot boxes (111.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Printed matter, writings, letters, photographs, and miscellany, relating to the Russian writers Isaak Babel', Boris Pasternak and Joseph Brodsky. Consists primarily of printed matter by and about Pasternak, Brodsky and Babel'.
Administrative Information
Access
Please note that some original Pasternak correspondence and writings in Box 22 are restricted, for which use copies are available in Box 20.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1998, with subsequent increments received through 2004. Additional increments are expected. An increment was added in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Irwin T. Holtzman is a prominent and enthusiastic bibliophile, who has spent a lifetime collecting books on a wide variety of subjects. He is especially interested in modern writers and the publication of their works since 1927, the year of his birth. He has made generous donations of several collections to academic and cultural institutions, both in the United States and abroad.
Of particular interest are his collections of modern American and American Indian authors, donated to the University of Michigan; an American literature collection in the Russian State Library; a collection of modern Israeli writers, housed in the Holtzman-Harman Room at the University of Jerusalem; and the present collection of Boris Pasternak, Leonid Pasternak, Isaac Babel, and Joseph Brodsky materials in the Hoover Institution Archives.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Irwin T. and Shirley Holtzman Collection consists mainly of material related to the life and work of the Russian authors Isaac Babel, Joseph Brodsky and Boris Pasternak. It also includes material related to the publication of their writings and the process of collecting these publications by I. T. Holtzman. The collection includes biographical material about the writers; their correspondence and writings; material related to conferences and exhibits about their work; photographs; phonotape cassettes and videotapes; as well as drawings, posters, memorabilia, and clippings. The bulk of the collection was acquired in 1998, with subsequent increments received through 2002.
The majority of the collection consists of printed copies of writings by the authors, as well as writings about or related to their work. Of special interest is material illustrating the process of publishing books by these authors, including the evolution of works through the stages of galley proofs, page proofs, printed wrappers, and sample pages. Also of interest are books signed or dedicated by the authors, as well as rare, early, and limited editions of their works. In the description, transliterations are supplied for non-Roman alphabets.
The Isaac Babel materials in the collection are noteworthy for their comprehensiveness. Irwin T. Holtzman has endeavored to collect all known materials published by or about Babel, including foreign translations. There are art works, video and sound recordings, conference materials, and marginalia, all related to Babel's life and work. Some of these materials are rare, and their being grouped as a whole makes them of interest to Babel scholars.
The Babel materials are organized by headings established by Mr. Holtzman, and they illustrate the art of collecting itself, with the various strands connecting Babel's life and work, as well as links among his contemporaries and interpreters, being made visible through the criteria used by the collector in selecting and organizing the Babel materials.
The Holtzman collection also contains a number of books by and about Leonid Pasternak, with illustrations of his paintings and drawings.
Please note that some original Pasternak correspondence and writings are restricted, for which use copies are available in Box 20.
Arrangement
Arranged into series by author, with additional author series for each additional increment of materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Russian literature.; Pasternak, Boris Leonidovich,1890-1960.; Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-; Babel', I.(Isaak), 1894-1941.; Holtzman, Shirley.
Collection Contents
- Joseph Brodsky File, 1956-2000.
  Appraisals, bibliographies, and packing lists; biographical material re Brodsky; clippings; his correspondence, speeches, and writings; material related to academic conferences and exhibits about Brodsky; writings about Brodsky; photographs and drawings of Brodsky; phonotape cassettes and videotapes of readings by or about Brodsky; posters related to his work and public appearances, memorabilia, and printed matter, including books, scholarly journals, and popular magazines, arranged by physical form. The extensive printed matter, at the end of the series, consists of publications by and about Joseph Brodsky, and is arranged chronologically by title or author, with the spellings conforming to those of the original publications. Transliterations are supplied for non-Roman alphabets
  - General
    - Bibliographies of Joseph Brodsky holdings
      - General, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 1: 1)
      - Holtzman Collection
        - General, 1993 (Folder 1: 2)
        - Bigelow, Thomas, "Joseph Brodsky: A Descriptive Bibliography,", 1994. (Folder 1: 3)
          Typescript
      - University libraries and the Library of Congress, 1996. (Folder 1: 4)
        Electronically generated lists
    - Bookseller's catalogs, 1978-1992 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Bookseller's catalogs, 1978-1992 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
    - Correspondence of Irwin T. Holtzman
      - General, 1987-1998 (Folder 2: 3)
      - Bigelow, Thomas, 1992-1994 (Folder 2: 4)
    - Miscellany (Folder 2: 5)
  - Biographical file, 1956-1996
    - Biographies and photocopy of "Lichnaia kartochka,", 1956. (Folder 2: 6)
    - Clippings
      - English language press, 1972-1996 (Folder 2: 7-9)
      - Russian language press
        - General, 1992 (Folder 2: 10)
        - Vechernii Leningrad, 1964 January 8 (Folder 2: 11)
    - Memorial service programs, 1996 (Folder 2: 12)
    - Obituaries, 1996 (Folder 2: 13)
    - Miscellany. (Folder 2: 14)
      Includes university magazines, catalogs, and other printed matter related to Brodsky's teaching career in the United States, 1991-1996
  - Conference file, 1995-1997
    - Commemorative Conference to Honor Joseph Brodsky, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1996 (Folder 2: 15)
      - General (Folder 2: 16)
      - Binder of material related to the conference (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - International Seminar, Helsinki, 1995. (Folder 3: 2)
      Program
    - III-ia Mezhdunarodnaia nauchnaia konferentsiia, posviashchennaia tvorchestvu Iosifa Brodskogo, 1997. (Folder 3: 3)
      Printed program
  - Correspondence, 1972-1990
    - Auden, W. H., 1972. (Folder 3: 4)
      Photocopy
    - Gowar, Michael, 1981 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Holtzman, I. T., 1986-1990 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Zweig, Paul, 1974-1977 (Folder 3: 7)
  - Exhibit file, 1996-1997
    - Commemorative Conference to Honor Joseph Brodsky, University of Michigan, Special Collections Library, 1996.; See also Conference file/Commemorative Conference to Honor Joseph Brodsky (Folder 3: 8)
      Program for the exhibit.
    - Muzei Anny Akhmatovoi, 1997.; See also Oversize file/Posters (Folder 3: 9)
      Flyer and announcement for memorial exhibit on the anniversary of Brodsky's death.
  - Speeches and writings, 1967-1996.; See also Printed matter for printed copies of books (Boxes 9-18)
    - General
      - General, 1967-1992. (Folder 3: 10)
        Clippings and photocopies
      - Poetry readings. Miscellany, including programs and reviews, 1972-1996 (Folder 3: 11)
    - "The Condition We Call Exile," (Folder 3: 12)
    - Elegy to John Donne and Other Poems, 1967. (Folder 3: 13)
      Page proof signed by author
    - "A Writer Is a Lonely Traveler," New York Times Magazine, 1972. (Folder 3: 14)
      Galley proof
    - Debut, Carl Proffer, trans., 1973. (Folder 3: 15)
      First edition printed wrappers. Signed by author
    - "Glaza i slezy," translation of Andrew Marvell, Russian Literature Tri-Quarterly, 1973. (Folder 3: 16)
      Holograph
    - Joseph Brodsky: Selected Poems, George L. Kline, trans., 1973
      - Printed wrappers stamped "Hand folded from Bloomsburg Craftsmen." Signed by author and translator (Folder 3: 17)
      - Page proofs with handwritten corrections by George Kline. Signed by author and translator (Folder 3: 18)
    - Preface to Kotlovan by Andrei Platonov, 1973. (Folder 3: 19)
      Includes page proofs for the English version, The Foundation Pit, 1973
    - A Part of Speech, 1980 (Box 4)
      - Galley proof (Folder 4: 1)
      - Page proof signed by author (Folder 4: 2)
      - Paperback with inscription by author (Folder 4: 3)
      - Revised proof (Folder 4: 4)
      - Sample page (Folder 4: 5)
    - Mramor, 1982
      - Programs for theater performance., See also Photographs (Folder 4: 6)
      - Uncorrected proof of translation with Alan Myers, 1989 (Folder 4: 7)
    - Stikhotvoreniia, 1986. (Folder 4: 8)
      Samizdat computer generated copy, obtained in Moscow
    - Commencement address, University of Michigan, 1988. (Folder 4: 9)
    - Interview, MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour, 1988. (Folder 4: 10)
      Typescript transcript
    - To Urania, 1988. (Folder 4: 11)
      Uncorrected proof signed by author
    - Commencement address, Dartmouth College, 1989. (Folder 4: 12)
    - Interview, Economist, 1990 October. (Folder 4: 13)
      Clipping
    - Interview, Nightline, ABC News, 1992. (Folder 4: 14)
      Printed transcript
    - "Review," 1995, a translation of "Predstavlenie" by Thomas Campbell. (Folder 4: 15)
  - Writings by others, 1970-1996
    - Kline, George, "Istoriia dvukh knig," and "A History of Brodsky's Ostanovka v Pustyne and His Selected Poems,", 1996. (Folder 4: 16)
    - Pospielovsky, Dmitrii, "Two Years of the Chronicle of Current Events,", 1970. (Folder 4: 17)
  - Photographs, 1968-1996 (Box 5)
    - 8 prints, including 1 print depicting the memorial plaque on his residence in St. Petersburg, 1964-1995 (Folder 5: 1)
    - 44 prints depicting the exhibit at the University of Michigan, Special Collections Library, 1996 (Folder 5: 2)
    - 6 prints depicting Brodsky in Mramor (Folder 5: 3)
    - 2 prints of Brodsky in Leningrad and San Francisco by Mikhail Lemkin, 1968-1988 (Folder 5: 4-5)
    - 1 oversize portrait print (Folder 5: 6)
  - Audio-visual file, 1986 and undated (Box 6)
    - Phonotape cassettes, n.d. (Box 6)
      - Unknown author, "Fear and the Muse: The Story of Anna Akhmatova" (Box 6)
      - Brodsky, Joseph (Box 6)
        - "Joseph Brodsky" (Box 6)
        - "Joseph Brodsky Reads His Poetry" (Box 6)
        - "A Maddening Space" (Box 6)
      - Kotliar, Boris, "Vorotishsia na rodinu: Stikhi Iosifa Brodskogo" (Box 6)
      - Leonard, John, review of Watermark (Box 6)
    - Videotapes
      - Brodsky, Joseph, "A Maddening Space,", n.d. (Box 6)
      - Pawlikowski, Paul, "Moscow-Pietushki,", n.d. (Box 6)
      - Rif, Vladimir, "When I Think of Russia,", 1986 (Box 6)
  - Oversize file, 1964-1996 (Box 7)
    - Drawings. Framed caricatures of Brodsky by David Levine, 1980 and 1995. (Box 7)
      Ink on paper
    - Phonorecord cover, "Iosif Brodskii: Ostanovka v pustyne," read by Mikhail Kozakov, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Posters (Box 7)
      - "Poetry in Motion," published by the Metropolitan Transit Authority, Boston, in cooperation with The Poetry Society of America, n.d. (Box 7)
      - Announcement for poetry reading, University of Michigan, 1975 (Box 7)
      - Announcement for memorial benefit concert in honor of Brodsky, St. Petersburg, 1996 February (Box 7)
    - Printed matter. 1972 god, Alan Myers, trans., 1989. (Box 7)
      Illustrated with woodcuts by Ilse Schreiber. Title on outside cover is 1927. Signed by Brodsky and Schreiber
  - Memorabilia. Two "matreshka" dolls with representations of Brodsky and other Russian writers, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Printed matter. Publications by and about Joseph Brodsky, arranged chronologically. Hardback, unless otherwise indicated., See also Oversize file/Printed matter (Box 9)
    - General
      - Dissertations on Brodsky submitted for Doctor of Philosophy degrees, 1978-1996 (Box 9)
      - Popular magazines with articles by or about Brodsky, 1968-1997 (Box 9)
    - Brodskij, Jossif, Reflexionen eines Ausgewiesenen. Paperback offprint, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, 1965 (Box 10)
    - TriQuarterly, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Vozdushnye puti: Al'manakh, R. N. Greenberg, ed., 1965 (Box 10)
    - Brodski, Iossip, Collines et autres poèmes, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Brodskij, Jossif, Ausgewählte Gedichte, 1966 (Box 10)
    - The New Russian Poets 1953 to 1966: An Anthology, George Reavey, ed. (Box 10)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Elegy to John Donne and Other Poems, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Vozdushnye puti: Al'manakh, R. N. Greenberg, ed., 1967 (Box 10)
    - Brodskij, Iosif, Velka Elegie, Edice Svedectvi, trans., 1968 (Box 10)
    - Carlyle, Olga, Poets on Street Corners, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Ostrov zari bagrianoi, S. Feikho, ed., 1968 (Box 10)
    - Reavy, George, The Russian Poets 1953-1968 (Box 10)
    - Russia's Underground Poets, Keith Bosely, trans., 1969. (Box 10)
      Includes inscription by Brodsky
    - Brodskii, Iosif, Stikhotvoreniia i Poemy, 1969. (Box 10)
      In Hebrew
    - Brown, Edward, Russian Literature Since the Revolution, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, Ostanovka v pustyne, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Brumberg, Abraham, In Quest of Justice, 1970 (Box 10)
    - The Literatures of the Soviet Peoples, Harri Junger, ed., 1970 (Box 10)
    - Novyi Zhurnal, R. Gul', ed., nos. 95, 97, 98, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
    - TriQuartely, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Brodski, Josif, Stanica u pustinji, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Carlyle, Olga and Rose Styron, Modern Russian Poetry, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Field, Andrew, The Complection of Russian Literature, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Russian Literature Triquarterly, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Antaeus, 1972 (Box 10)
    - Index on Censorship, 1972 (Box 10)
    - Massie, Suzanne, The Living Mirror, 1972 (Box 10)
    - New American and Canadian Poetry, 1972 (Box 10)
    - The American Poetry Review, vol. 2, vos. 1-2, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Selected Poems, George Kline, trans., Harper and Row, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Partisan Review, vol. XL, no. 2, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Platonov, Andrei, Kotlovan, 1973. (Box 11)
      Includes English version, The Foundation Pit, 1973
    - Poetry from the Russian Underground, Langland et al., ed., 1973 (Box 11)
    - Ensemble 5: Internationales Jahrbuch für Literatur, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Index on Censorship, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Modern Russian Poets on Poetry, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Postwar Russian Poetry, Daniel Weissbort, ed., 1974 (Box 11)
    - The Ghent Quarterly: A Review of the Arts, no. 1, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Three Slavic Poets, John Rezek, ed., 1975 (Box 11)
    - W. H. Auden, Stephen Spender, ed., 1975 (Box 11)
    - Russian Literature Triquarterly, Carl R. Proffer, ed., Winter 1975 (Box 11)
    - Cohen, Arthur, A Hero in His Time, 1976 (Box 11)
    - Kontinent, 1976 (Box 11)
    - Kontinent 1, 1976 (Box 11)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1977 (Box 11)
      - Chast' Rechi (Box 11)
      - Konets Prekrasnoi Epokhi (Box 11)
    - Brodskij, Jossif, Einem alten Architekten in Rom, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Glagol, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Osip Mandelstam, Bernard Meares, trans., 1977 (Box 11)
    - Partisan Review 4, 1977 (Box 11)
    - 10 Bibliographies of 20th Century Russian Literature, Fred Moody, ed., 1977 (Box 11)
    - Wechsberg, Joseph, In Leningrad, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Modern Poetry in Translation, Summer 1977 (Box 11)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Poems and Translations, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Brown, Deming, Soviet Russian Literature Since Stalin, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Etkind, Efim, Notes of a Non-Conspirator, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Kontinent 3, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Platonov, Andrei, Collected Works, 1978 (Box 12)
    - La Délirante: Revue de poésie, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Tsvetaeva, Marina, Stikhotvoreniia i Poemy, vols. 1-5, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, 1980 (Box 12)
      - Chast' Rechi (Box 12)
      - A Part of Speech (Box 12)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Verses on the Winter Campaign, Alan Myers, trans., 1980 (Box 12)
      Hardback and offprints
    - Kiš, Danilo, A Tomb for Boris Davidivich, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Columbia: A Magazine of Poetry and Prose, Spring/Summer 1980 (Box 12)
    - Pond, Elizabeth, From the Yaroslavsky Station, 1981 (Box 12)
    - Iowa Review, Fall 1981 (Box 12)
    - Russica 1981, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Brodski, Josif, Spiew Wahadla, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, Rimskie Elegii, 1982 (Box 12)
    - The Paris Review, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Akhmatova, Anna, Poems, Lyn Coffin, trans., 1983 (Box 12)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, Novye stansy k Avguste, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Modern Poetry in Translation: 1983, Daniel Weissbrot, ed. (Box 12)
    - Walcott, Derek, Poems of the Caribbean, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, Mramor, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Kreps, Mikhail, O poezii Iosifa Brodskogo, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Ripp, Victor, Moscow to Main St.: Among the Russian Emigres, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Salisbury, Harrison, The Book Enchained, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Williams College: One Hundred and Ninety-Fifth Commencement Addresses, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Terras, Victor, Handbook of Russian Literature, 1985 (Box 12)
    - The Ontario Review, Fall-Winter 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Aleshkovsky, Yuz, Kangaroo, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Less than One, 1986 (Box 13)
    - The Best American Essays 1986, Elizabeth Hardwick, ed. (Box 13)
    - The Blue Lagoon: Anthology of Modern Russian Poetry, K. K. Kuzminsky and G. Kovalev, eds., 1986 (Box 13)
    - Partisan Review 3, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Poetika Brodskogo, L. V. Losev, ed., 1986 (Box 13)
    - Ratushinskaya, Irina, No I'm not Afraid, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Azbel, Mark, Ya Refusenik, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, Uraniia, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Less than One, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Novyi Mir, no. 12, 1987 (Box 13)
    - An Age Ago: A Selection of Nineteenth-CeBoxntury Russian Poetry, Alan Myers, trans., 1988 (Box 13)
    - Brodskij, Iosif, Dall'esilio, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, To Urania, 1988. (Box 13)
      Hardback and paperback
    - Separated at Birth? A Spy Book, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Poets and Writers, March/April 1988 (Box 13)
    - Akhmatovskii Sbornik, S. Dediulin and G. Superfin, eds., 1989 (Box 13)
    - Brodskij, Iosif, Fondamenta degli incurabili, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Marbles, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Nayman, Anatoly, Remembering Anna Akhmatova, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Polukhina, Valentina, Joseph Brodsky: A Poet for Our Time, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Aleshkovsky, Yuz, The Hand, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1990 (Box 14)
      - Chast' rechi: Izbrannye stikhi (Box 14)
      - Nazidanie (Box 14)
      - Osennii krik iastreba (Box 14)
      - Primechaniia paporotnika (Box 14)
      - Razmerom podlinnika (Box 14)
      - Stikhotvoreniia (Box 14)
    - Brodsky's Poetics and Aesthetics, Lev Loseff and Valentina Polukhina, eds., 1990 (Box 14)
    - Eisen, Jonathan, The Glasnost' Reader, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Granta, no. 30, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Iakimchuk, Nikolai, Delo Io. Brodskogo, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Slovo-Word, no. 9, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Stikhotvoreniia Iosifa BrodBoxle, G. F. Komarov, ed., 1990 (Box 14)
    - Volkova, Marina and Solomon Volkov, Iosif Brodskii v N'iu Iiorke, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Anisimov, Evgenii Peterburgskii mirazh, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1991 (Box 14)
      - Ballada o malen'kom buksire (Box 14)
      - Kholmy (Box 14)
      - Pis'ma rimskomu drugu (Box 14)
      - Stikhotvoreniia (Box 14)
    - Davidson, Michael et al., Leningrad: American Writers in the Soviet Union, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Kushner, Aleksandr, Apollo in the Snow, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Montenegro, David, Points of Departure, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Poliakov, Lev, Russia: A Portrait, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Rein, Evgenii, Protiv chasovoi strelki, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Akhmatova, Anna, My Half Century, Ronald Meyer, ed., 1992 (Box 14)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1992 (Box 14)
      - Bog sokhraniaet vse (Box 14)
      - Forma vremeni, vols. I and II (Box 14)
      - Naberezhnaia neiztselimykh (Box 14)
      - Rozhdestvenskie stikhi, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, 1992 (Box 14)
      - Flight From Byzantium. In Hebrew (Box 14)
      - Sochineniia Iosifa Brodskogo, vols. I-IV (Box 14)
      - Watermark. Hardback, paperback (Box 14)
    - Fragment 10, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Iliukovich, A., Soglasno Zaveshchaniiu, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Partisan Review/4, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Polukhina, Valentina, 1992 (Box 14)
      - Brodskii glazami sovremennikov (Box 14)
      - Brodsky Through the Eyes of His Contemporaries (Box 14)
    - Rein, Evgenii, Izbrannoe, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Volkov, S., Brodskii ob Akhmatovoi, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Volkova, M. and Dovlatov, S., 1992 (Box 14)
      - Ne tol'ko Brodskii (Box 14)
      - Not Just Brodsky (Box 14)
    - PMLA, March 1992 (Box 14)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1993 (Box 15)
      - Izbrannoe (Box 15)
      - Kappadokiia: Stikhi (Box 15)
    - Conversations in Exile: Russian Writers Abroad, John Glad, ed., 1993 (Box 15)
    - Efimov, Igor', Bremia dobra, 1993 (Box 15)
    - First Anthology: 30 Years of the New York Review of Books, Barbara Epstein and Robert Silvers, eds., 1993 (Box 15)
    - Russkaia Literatura XX veka: Issledovaniia amerikanskikh uchenykh, B. Averin, ed., 1993 (Box 15)
    - Altogether Elsewhere: Writers on Exile, Marc Robinson, ed., 1994 (Box 15)
    - Bethea, David, Joseph Brodsky and the Creation of Exile, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Brodski, Josif, Zamiec w Massachusetts, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1994 (Box 15)
      - Isaak i Avraam. Illustrated by Mikhail Karacik. Limited edition (Box 15)
      - Izbrannye stikhotvoreniia, 1957-1992, 1994 (Box 15)
      - Persian Arrow. Illustrated with etchings by Edik Steinberg (Box 15)
      - Vertumn. Poetry of Joseph Brodsky, illustrated by Vadim Kulakov (Box 15)
    - Liberman, Alexander, Campidoglio: Michelangelo's Roman Capitol, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Miloslavsky, Yury, Urban Romances, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Octavio Paz: A Celebration, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Polivanov, Konstantin, Anna Akhmatova and Her Circle, 1994 (Box 15)
    - The Wilson Quarterly, Autumn 1994 (Box 15)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1995 (Box 16)
      - Peizazh s navodneniem. (Box 16)
      - Peresechennaia mestnost' (Box 16)
      - V okrestnostiakh Atlantidy (Box 16)
    - Brodskij, Iosif, Marmi, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Lemkhin, Mikhail, Missing Frames, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Polukhina, Valentina, Slovar' tropov Brodskogo, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Samoilov, D., Pamiatnye zapiski, 1995 (Box 16)